# AUSTIN TAM

Tustin, CA 92782 | Cell Phone: (714) 688 - 6398 | Email: austintaivi@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | Website

### **SUMMARY**

Recent graduate with a deep interest in data analytics and visualization and equipped with problem solving and ideation skills. Experienced in a variety of tools used in the data analytics world and skilled in data wrangling, analysis and reporting.

# **SKILLS**

- ♦ Proficient Data Wrangling, Visualization, and Analysis in R and Python
- ♦ Regression Analysis in Stata
- ♦ Data Querying, and Analysis in SQL
- Storytelling and Visualization creation in Tableau
- Data Analysis and Reporting in Excel

#### **DATA EXPERIENCES**

#### **UCSB Economics Department** | Econ 145 TA

June 2022 - August 2022

Worked with a team, helped to create autograders for over twenty different homeworks. The team mainly coded in R and used Github, as well as R Studio, to share work and data files.

# Data Hackathon | Participant

March 2021 - November 2021

- Participated in a quarter long hackathon, where students learned intermediate skills in R, such as web scraping, pdf scraping, various methods using packages such as ggplot2, tidyverse, and kblExtra.
- ♦ Team focused on visualizing the enormity of the threat that wildfires pose in California. Using data derived from using pdf scraping methods, the team created a multitude of visualizations, including a GIF of all the wildfires in the past thirty years in California.

# OTHER EXPERIENCES

#### Worldhealer Nonprofit | Academic Committee Member

June 2021 - August 2021

- ♦ Collaborated in small groups to create a multitude of academic resources for K-12 students on a variety of global topics to transform students into a more inclusive and understanding community
- Generated \$100 by independently organizing a sticker fundraiser and managing an Etsy store

August 2019 - June 2022

#### **UCSB Athletic Performance Center** | Student Manager

- Managed all aspects of staffing for 17 team members and compiled new training schedules every 3 months
- ♦ Facilitated smooth functioning of gym by managing email communication between the Head Coach, staff members, and sport club team leaders biweekly
- Interviewed new hires and train new staff members to comply with athlete and facility safety regulations

# **UCSB Athletic Performance Center** | APC Specialist

October 2018 - June 2022

- Designed and modify workout programs to help athletes maximize their potential, build strength to optimize physical capabilities during on and off seasons, and ensure safety both in and outside of the weightroom
- ♦ Worked with athletes 1-on-1 in order to teach and correct form for lifts to maximize safety and efficacy

## **EDUCATION**

**University of California, Santa Barbara** B.A. in Philosophy and Economics

September 2018 - June 2022

GPA: 3.85 | High Honors | L&S Honors (2019 - 2022